Guide to the Chamberlain-Cravens-Cullinan family papers, 1900-2010 MS 594
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series IV: Genealogy, 173570
  - Subseries C: E-mails (by geographic region), 173590
    - Ireland, Clare County (3 of 3), 179126 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Ireland, General, 179127 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Kentucky, 179128 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Missouri, 179129 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Ohio, 179130 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Oklahoma, 179131 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania, 179132 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Tennessee, 179133 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Tennessee, Rhea County, 179134 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Subseries D: General Research, 179135
    - Ancestry List (1 of 2), 179136 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Ancestry List (2 of 2), 179137 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Assembly, 179138 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Chamberlain, Anne, 179139 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Chamberlain, Charles, 179140 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Cravens, James Rorick, 179141 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Cravens Chamberlain, Mary, 179142 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Cullinan, J.S. Materials, 179143 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - "D.O.", 179144 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Family Finder Report, 179145 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Family History 1, 179146 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Family History 2, 179147 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Family History 3, 179148 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Family Record, 179149 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Family Tree, 179150 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - The Humble Way, Sept./Oct. 1951, 179151 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Indian Land Cessions, 179152 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Keighley, 1880. Christmas Murder, 179153 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - KnowX.com, 179154 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Lincoln, Abraham Ancestry, 179155 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Maps, 179156 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Merkin, W.S. Interview, 179157 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Misc. Family Files, 179158 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1920s, 179159 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1930s, 179160 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1940s, 179161 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1950s, 179162 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1960s, 179163 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1970s, 179164 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980s, 179165 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1990s, 179166 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Newspaper Clippings, n.d., 179167 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Quakers, 179168 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Rains, 179169 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Rootsweb, 179170 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Smith, Alfred Publications, 179171 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Unidentified, 179172 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Subseries E: Audio and Visual Materials, 173591
    - Family History CDs: Atlantic, Southern, and Midwest census data, 1600-1950, 179173 (Box 24)
      General
      The compact discs (cd) in this box contain genealogical information derived from otherwise public sources, such as U.S. census data, and are presented in a proprietary software "Family Tree Maker" format dating from circa 2000. The discs are open for research but the needed software for viewing is not part of the archive. No attempt to preserve the content of these discs has been made by the archive, due to the availability of the data in other public formats and the restrictive issue of the proprietary software.
    - Atlantic, Midwest and Southern States, Census and Family name data from 1700-1900, 179174 (Box 25)
    - Atlantic and Southern States, Germany and U.K. 1600-1900, 179175 (Box 26)
- Series V: Books, Memorabilia, Ephemera, and Printed Materials, 173571
  - Augusta (Donna) Ferguson Cravens Recipe book, 1895-1900, 179176 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Augusta (Donna) Ferguson Cravens Journal, 1897, 179177 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Augusta (Donna) Ferguson Cravens Journal, 1897, 179178 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Songs of Dartmouth College-Rorick Cravens, 1900-1920, 179179 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Diary, 1916, 179180 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Mary Cullinan High School Scrapbook, 1917-1918, 179181 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Diary, 1918, 179182 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Mary Cullinan-"Daily Theme," October-November 1919, 179183 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Mary Cullinan Diary, 1919, 179184 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Rorick Cravens-Dartmouth yearbook, 1922, 179185 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - J.S. Cullinan donor book, 1910-1920, 179186 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Mary C. Cullinan log book, 1920, 179187 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Geography Notebook, 1921, 179188 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Art Notebook, 1921, 179189 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Botany Notebook, 1921, 179190 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Household Management Notebook, 1926, 179191 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Mary C. Cullinan notebook, 1927, 179192 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Mary Cullinan Guest Book, 1930-1943, 179193 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Rorick and Mary Cravens Hawaii Vacation album, 1931, 179194 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. Rorick Cravens medical and housekeeping notes, 1930s-1950s, 179195 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Augusta Cravens memorial book, 1951, 179196 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Nancy Cravens and Charles Chamberlain wedding guest book, April 30, 1954, 179197 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Nina Cullinan Cookbook, 1940-1960, 179198 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Baby's first book, 1956, 179199 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Anne Wesley Chamberlain, baby book, 1957, 179200 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Mary Cravens Chamberlain-baby book, 1957, 179201 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Laura Roberts Chamberlain-baby book, October 1961, 179202 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Rorick Cravens Scrapbook pages, glass panel donation to Universith of Houston, October 1968, 179203 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - James Rorick Cravens Funeral Book, August 20, 1976, 179204 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - James Rorick Cravens Funeral guest book, August 20, 1976, 179205 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Rorick Cravens Memorial, 1976, 179206 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - James Rorick Cravens Funeral Guest book-house, August 20, 1976, 179207 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Shadyside Article-The Houston Review, Winter 1980, 179208 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Cullinan Park dedication, 1981-1982, 179209 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Nina Cullinan-Houston Festival Brochure, March 1982, 179210 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain-M.A. thesis, University of Houston, December 1985, 179211 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain-M.A. thesis, University of Houston, December 1985, 179212 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1986, 179213 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1988, 179214 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1989, 179215 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1990, 179216 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1991, 179217 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Appraisal Report-Real Estate, Estes Park, CO, 1992, 179218 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1992, 179219 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1994, 179220 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1996, 179221 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Nancy Chamberlain-journal, 1996, 179222 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain-Grandmother book, 1997, 179223 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1997, 179224 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Country Diary, 1999, 179225 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Ann Chamberlain – Country Diary, 2000, 179226 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - A manual of ocean travel- Donna Ferguson, 1898, 179227 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Donna Cravens- Recipe book, n.d., 179228 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Recettes ex Quises, 1905-1910, 179229 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Donna Cravens-101 Entrees, 1906, 179230 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Donna Cravens – 101 Salads, 1906, 179231 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Donna Cravens-101 Chafing Dish Recipes, 1906, 179232 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Donna Cravens-101 Sandwiches, 1908, 179233 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Diary-Summer, 1916, 179234 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Planner, 1920-1925, 179235 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Diary, 1920, 179236 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Diary, 1921, 179237 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Mary C. Cullinan Travel Diary, 1922, 179238 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - J.R. Cravens-Princeton Song Book, 1922, 179239 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Mary C. Cullinan-Diary 1925, 179240 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Mary C. Cravens-Notebooks, 1926, 179241 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Mary C. Cullinan-Planners, 1926-1929, 179242 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - River Oaks Country Club Information, 1927, 179243 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Mary Cravens-Planner, 1930, 179244 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Nancy Tuttle Cravens-Baby Book, 1932, 179245 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. Rorick Cravens Diary, 1938, 179246 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Mary C. Cravens-Medical Notes, 1940-1950, 179247 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Nancy Cravens-Diary, 1946, 179248 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Anne Wesley Chamberlain-Baptism Book, 1956, 179249 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Mary Cravens Chamberlain Baby Book, October 1957; 179349 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Mary Cullinan Cravens-Prayer Book, 1958-1978; 179350 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Mary Cullinan Cravens-Notebook, 1960-1965; 179351 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Ann Chamberlain-Autograph Book, 1971; 179352 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Mary Cravens-Trip Diary, 1977; 179353 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Mary Cravens-Trip Diaries, 1978-1982; 179354 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Mary Cravens-Trip Diary, 1983-1984; 179355 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Charles Chamberlain III-Diary, 1982; 179356 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - Laura Carmichael-Travel Diary, Summer 1982; 179357 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Unidentified journal, n.d.; 179358 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Mary Cullinan Cravens- address book, 179359 (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - Charles D. Chamberlain Baby book, 1964; 179360 (Box 31)
  - Nancy Chamberlain Girl Scout Scrapbook, Troop 109, 1942-1943; 179361 (Box 32)
  - Mary C. Cravens Houston High School Your Book, n.d.; 179362 (Box 33)
  - Mary C. Cravens Scrapbooks, 1920, 1934, c. 1952, 1962-67, 1968, n.d.; 179363 (Box 34-38)
  - Oversize Certificates, 179364 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials-Texas Churchman, 1956; 179365 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials-Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, November 1976; 179366 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials-100 Most Influential People of the Petroleum Century, n.d.; 179367 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material-Junior League Circus, May 10-11, 1927; 179368 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials-Junior League Magazine, May 1932; 179369 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Printed Materials-Town & Country, March 1954; 179370 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - TC's Treasure Mart, 179371 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Bronze Card Printing Plates, Mr. & Mrs. James Cravens, Nancy Cravens, 179372 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo County Campaign posters, 179373 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Country Dance rosters & ephemera, 1938; 179374 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Dance cards, 179375 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Drawings, poems, and essays, 179376 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Drivers' licenses and passports, 179377 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Eulogies, 179378 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Golf, 179381 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Guns & Hunting, 179382 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Horoscopes and handwriting analysis, 179383 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Maps, 179384 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous medical records, 1920-1976; 179385 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Nancy Chamberlain trip to Scotland, 1994; 179386 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Receipts, 179387 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Rorick Cravens-Military Service, 179388 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Small cards and tickets, 179389 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Small paper art, 179390 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Brochures and address/speeches, 179391 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Programs and menus, 179392 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Recipes, 179393 (Box 39, Folder 21-22)
  - Newsclippings-birth and marriage announcements, 179394 (Box 39a, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings-S.P. Rail Line Injunction, 1925; 179395 (Box 39a, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings-Hoover's visit to Houston, 1925; 179396 (Box 39a, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings- Houston Commentary, 179397 (Box 39a, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings-Mt. Rushmore, 179398 (Box 39a, Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings-Cultural commentary, 1960s; 179399 (Box 39a, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings-Houston society, 179400 (Box 39a, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings-Barbara Cullinan will lawsuit, 179401 (Box 39a, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings-AE (George W. Russell), 1928; 179402 (Box 39a, Folder 9)
  - Newclippings-Obituaries, 179403 (Box 39a, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings-Lucie Halm Cullinan's death, 179404 (Box 39a, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings-Houston Arts & culture, 179405 (Box 39a, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings-Nina Cullinan, 179406 (Box 39a, Folder 13)
  - Newsclippings-Debutants, 179407 (Box 39a, Folder 14)
  - Newclippings-Cartoons, 179408 (Box 39a, Folder 15)
  - Newsclippings-school related, 179409 (Box 39a, Folder 16)
  - Newsclippings-unidentified, 179410 (Box 39a, Folder 17)
  - Magazine clippings, 179411 (Box 39a, Folder 18)
  - Certificates, 179412 (Box 39a, Folder 19)
  - Plaque-Riverside General Hospital-50th year appreciation award, October 30, 1975; 179413 (Box 39a, Folder 20)
  - Mary Catherine Cullinan's lace baby cap [ca. 1901] and letters re: birth, [October 1901]; 179414 (Box 39a, Folder 21)
  - Nancy Cravens Movie Star Scrapbook, 179415 (Box 39b)
  - Cullinan family tree, 1796-1990s; 180946 (Box 39b)
- Series VI: Audio and Visual Materials, 173572
  Scope and Contents
  Box 40 contains Audio/Visual materials made by the family, including 8mm films, VHS tapes, and audio tapes described at the item level.
  - 8 mm film: 4 Longfellow, hunting farm, East Barnard, tennis, Chamberlains and Sissy, cattle- East Bernard, engagement day San Antonio - March 1954, bluebonnets, Easter, tennis matches, winter and spring 1954, 179379 (Box 40, Item 1)
  - 8 mm film: Our honeymoon at Nazral(?) farm- Washington TX, Osteen beach party – Galveston, Houston - maids, Medical school-Galveston, May 1954, 179416 (Box 40, Item 2)
  - 8 mm film: Gettysburg November 1954, Lake Placid Christmas 1954, Skiing at Bennets, Longwood Gardens, Washington March 1955, Easter Parade New York, Spring in Philadelphia, our anniversary 1955, 179417 (Box 40, Item 3)
  - 8 mm film: unlabeled, 179418 (Box 40, Item 4-9)
  - 8 mm film: Japan December 1956 – March 1957, 179419 (Box 40, Item 10)
  - 8 mm film: unlabeled, 179420 (Box 40, Item 11)
  - 8 mm film: Japan, 179421 (Box 40, Item 12)
  - 8 mm film: unlabeled, 179422 (Box 40, Item 13-23)
  - VHS: Sour Lake's well #3 90th Anniversary Celebration March 15, 1993, 179423 (Box 40, Item 24)
  - VHS: Ray Miller/Texaco, Steve Smith's Sunday, KHOU-TV (CBS) May 23, 1993, 179424 (Box 40, Item 25)
  - Scotch recording tape 7" reel: Mt. Olive Baptist Church December 1967, 179425 (Box 40, Item 26-28)
  - Sealed metal box imprinted with "China", 4" x 2 ¾ " x 2", 179426 (Box 40, Item 29)
  - Audiodisc-James Cravens-Ranch Cravens talk, 1934, 179427 (Box 40, Item 30)
- Series VII: Oversize Materials, 179380
  - Resurvey of Malcolm Cravens 1995.09 acre tract out of Pat McGloin Survey A-28, Live Oak County, TX May 15, 1969, 179428 (Drawer 69, Item 49)
  - Planting plan for ground adjoining residence of Mr. J.S. Cullinan, Shadyside on linen, Jan. 1920, 179429 (Drawer 69, Item 50)
  - View of fireplace, sketch on tracing paper, n.d., 179430 (Drawer 69, Item 51)
  - Plat of J.R. Cravens 77 acre in F Pettus Survey, Colorado County, TX, n.d., 179431 (Drawer 69, Item 52)
  - Pencil drawing "Carden Bailey" April 1938, 179432 (Drawer 69, Item 53)
  - Planting plan Cravens Parkway-Hermann Park, October 1, 1976, 179433 (Drawer 69, Item 54)
  - Map of Cravens Park, November 17, 1968, 179434 (Drawer 69, Item 55)
  - Section of couch for Miss N. Cullinan; Smith, Hegner & Moore, Architects, 179435 (Drawer 69, Item 56)
  - Residence for Miss N. Cullinan, changes and additions, October 15, 1948, 179436 (Drawer 69, Item 57)
  - View from southwest, flat roof two-level [house], sketch and initial sketch, n.d., 179437 (Drawer 69, Item 58)
  - Plaque-Riverside General Hospital 50th year appreciation award presented to the family of Joseph S. Cullinan, October 30, 1975, 179438 (Drawer 69, Item 59)
  - Diploma-Rorick Cravens Princeton University, [1873], 179439 (Drawer 69, Item 60)